어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes a life dazzle
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!!
여행하며 에도토피아에 향하던 무사시는 이하 닌자를 이끄는 한조에게 붙잡히고 말았다.
While heading to Edotopia, Musashi was captured by Hanzō, the leader of Iga ninjas.
그러나 코지로가 도와 구사일생한 무사시.
But thanks to Kojirō, Musashi escaped by the skin of his teeth.
지팡구 무예 대회를 노리고 계속 동쪽으로 가고 있었다.
He kept heading to the east, hoping to participate in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition.
사내 이시마츠
우정이 떨어지오
A Man Ishimatsu
Friendship Falls
시미즈 항의 명물은 차의 향기와 협객.
Shimizu Harbor is famous for the smell of tea and chivalrous men.
라고 노래불리어졌던 곳이 이곳, 시미즈 항이다.
That is how this place Shimizu Harbor is, according to a folk song.
기다리시오! 기다리시오!
Wait! Wait for me-dasu!
기다리시오! 코지로! 오늘로 결판을 내소!
Wait for me-dasu! We'll settle this as of today-dasu!
흥. 또 시끄러운 놈에게 발견됐군.
Hmph. That noisy brat again.
젠장! 또 업신여기지 마시오!
Damn! Don't make fun of me again-dasu!
자, 승부보시오!
Now! Have a match-dasu!
싸움이다!
There's a fight!
자, 코지로! 꺼내시오!
Now, Kojirō, pull it out-dasu!
흥. 옛 사람이 말하길, 바보는 죽지 않으면 바로잡히지 않는다 하지.
Hmph. According to people of the past, an idiot won't be cured without ying.
뭐라 했소?
What's that-dasu?!
이것도 널 위해서다. 한번은 내가 고쳐줄까.
This is also for you. Maybe I'll cure you for once.
잠깐! 잠깐잠깐! 잠깐!
Wait! Waitwait! Wait!
그 싸움! 잠깐!
That fight! Just a moment!
멈춰도 소용없소!
You're not stopping us-dasu!
자식! 누가 멈추랬냐! 싸움을 할 거라면 이 이시마츠 님을 동료로 삼지 않겠나!
Idiot! I never said you to stop! If you're going to fight, why not have me, Ishimatsu, as your comrade?
이시마츠
Ishimatsu
자! 나쁜 쪽이 누구냐!
Now! Tell me who's on the bad side!
너냐!
Is it you?!
아니면 너냐!
Or is it you?!
이게! 무예가끼리의 생명을 건 진검승부이오!
Hey, this is a real match done by risking our lives-dasu!
재미로 끼어들면 방해되오!
If you join for fun, it would bother us-dasu!
이 자식이!
You brat!
뭘 말대꾸냐. 화재하고 싸움은 화려하게 눈길을 끌지 않으면 재미없잖아!
What are you blabbering about? A fight and a fire are not fun if it's not attention-seeking!
자! 일어나라, 일어나!
Now, get up! Get up!
잘도 무예가의 머리를 때렸겠소!
How dare you hit the head of a Martial Artist-dasu!
꽤 하는 놈이군, 이 자식! 재밌어!
You do pretty well, brat! Interesting!
이러면 안 되지. 이 녀석을 잊었어.
No, I can't. I forgot about this.
뭔 일이오? 살면서 즐길만한 일에 대해 이야기하다가 갑자기 겁이 났소?
What's the problem-dasu? I guess you suddenly got scared during talking about what's good in the life-dasu?
이자식! 누가 너같은 돌팔이 무예가에게 기가 죽을까 보냐!
Brat! Who'd get frightened by a quack Martial Artist?!
어떠냐! 칼 따위 안 쓰고도 이걸로 충분하지!
Saw that? This is enough; a sword is overkill!
나 완전히 화났소!
I am completely mad now-dasu!
그런 무딘 칼, 손댈 것도 없다! 자! 어디서든 덤벼들어 봐라!
I don't have to touch such blunt sword! You may pounce on me from anywhere you want!
왜? 네 쪽이야말로 결국에는 이 몸의 펀치에 겁먹었냐?
What's the problem? Are you frightened by my punch?
흥! 그딴 펀치. 애초에 때릴 때부터 아프지도 않았소.
Hmph. I didn't feel a pain in the first place with that punch-dasu!
단지 난... 칼을 쓰지 않는 자에게 칼로 덤비는 것은 무예가로서의 자존심이 용서할 수 없을 뿐이오.
It's just that... my pride as a Martial Artist does not forgive attacking an opponent without sword using one-dasu.
오, 돌팔이 무예가 주제에 근성만은 훌륭하구나?
Oh, at least your spirit is high, for a quack Martial Artist!
돌팔이만은 말이 과하오!
I still cannot forgive calling me a quack!
흥. 수준 떨어지는 놈들. 사이좋게 잘들 놀고 있어라.
Hmph. Those low-classes. I hope you play together for a while.
뚱땡이 압사!
Fat pressure!
무슨, 이쯤이야!
This is nothing!
밧줄이오! 밧줄을 주시오, 밧줄!
Rope! Give me a rope-dasu! A rope!
헤! 돌팔이 주제에 꽤 하네?
Huh! You're pretty good for a quack!
그쪽이야말로 꽤나 특이하오.
Conversely, you're pretty interesting-dasu.
헤! 자랑은 아니지만 이 이시마츠 님은 말이다! 그걸 알아챈 놈이 참 싫다!
Hmph! Not trying to brag, but I, Ishimatsu, really hates anyone who realized that I am interesting!
간다!
Here it goes!
너... 돌머리구나.
Your head is like a stone.
그쪽이야말로.
Same for you too.
-뭐였어?
-저 바보들.
-What was it all about?
-Idiots.
그렇구나, 무사시!
I see, Musashi!
너, 지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾼다고? 아까 찔리는 줄 알았다!
Did you say that you're looking to be the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu? I thought I was almost stabbed by ya!
이시마츠 씨도 꽤 하오.
You do pretty well too-dasu, Mr. Ishimatsu.
흥! 당연하지! 기만은 아니지만 이 이시마츠 님은 말이다, 우는 아이도 뚝 그치게 하는 지로초 일가에서도 제일 잘 싸우지!
Hmph, of course! Not trying to brag, but I, Ishimatsu,
is the number one fighter of Jirochou family, which just saying the name will make a babyt shut up!
어?
Huh?
차
TEA
오, 무사시, 저기에 한숨 쉬지 않겠나.
Hey, Musashi, wanna take a rest there?
아니, 나, 그럴 돈이...
That is, I don't have money...
멍청아! 너, 그런 거 신경쓰지 마! 이 이시마츠 님이 잘 알고 있으니까!
Idiot! You shouldn't think too much about those matters! I, Ishimatsu, knows the best!
어라, 때릴 때 힘을 너무 줬나.
Huh, maybe I hit him too hard.
기다리셨습니다.
Here is your order!
우와! 난 단고를 보면 눈이 돌아가오!
Whoa! I get dizzy in front of dangos!
그렇구나, 그래! 무사시, 너, 오카야마에서 태어났다고?
Go ahead, as much as you want! Musashi, you said you were born at Okayama, right?
그렇소. 미야모토 마을에서 나왔소.
Right. I've came from Miyamoto village-dasu.
어, 먹어라, 먹어! 단고라도 얼마든지 먹어라!
Eat, eat! Eat your dangos!
그럼 사양않고!
Then, without hesitation!
무사시, 난 네가 마음에 들었다!
Musashi, I think I like your attitude and whatsoever!
나도 이시마츠 씨가 정말 좋소!
I really like Mr. Ishimatsu too!
오? 기쁜 소리를!
Oh? That's happy to hear!
어떠냐, 무사시. 너, 나하고 형제가 되지 않을래?
How's this, Musashi? Would you want to be a brother with me?
어? 형제라니, 나하고 이시마츠 씨를 낳은 어머니는 다르오.
Huh? Our mothers are different-dasu!
자식! 무엇도 진짜 형제가 되자는 게 아냐!
Idiot! I'm not telling you to be a biological brother!
마음속으로부터 친구가 되는 거야!
I'm telling you to be a friend deep in the hearts!
친구?
Friend?
왜 그래, 무사시. 나하고 친구 되는 게 싫어?
Why, Musashi? Would you hate becoming friend with me?
아니, 아니오!
No, that's not it-dasu!
난 지금까지 친구가 되자는 말을 들은 적이 없으니까...
I was never told to become friend from someone-dasu...
잠깐! 기다리시오!
Wait! Wait for me-dasu!
그러니까 난폭한 놈 무사시하고 놀지 말라 했잖아.
That's why I told you not to play with that violent Musashi!
다시는 안 그럴게.
I'll never do so again.
벌써 돌아가오? 좀 더 놉소!
Are you going back already-dasu? Let's play more-dasu!
자, 자! 밥 다 됐을 테니까 빨리 돌아가자!
Now, let's go back right now, as the food should be ready!
네!
Yay!
어째서이오! 더 놉소!
Why is that-dasu? Let's play more-dasu!
무사시도 돌아가.
Musashi should go back too.
또 놉소! 나하고 같이 놉소!
Let's play again-dasu! Play with me-dasu!
그랬소.
It happened.
뭘 그리 기운이 죽었냐! 자, 형제의 잔을 주고받자꾸나!
Why so blue? Hey, let's exchange the cup of brothers!
어이! 누나! 술 가져와줘!
Hey, sister! Get us liquors!
여기선 술은 다루지 않습니다!
We don't offer liquors!
쳇, 버릇없는 가게군!
Hmph, what an unprepared place!
뭐, 어쩔 수 없지. 대신 이 단고으로 끝낼까!
Well, I can't really do something about this. Let's end this with dangos!
자! 형제! 잘 부탁한다!
Brother! Looking forwards of us!
나도 잘 부탁하오.
I also look forwards of us-dasu!
근데 이시마츠 씨, 왜 칼 안 꺼냈소?
But, Mr. Ishimatsu, why didn't you pull out your sword-dasu?
그거야 이 때문이야.
That is because of this.
어? 그게 뭣이오?
Huh? What's that-dasu?
사실 나는 지로초 보스 대신 신사에 대신 참배하러 가고 있었어.
Actually, I was going to go to a temple to worship for our boss, Jirochou.
그 도중에 칼싸움 소동이 일어난다면 모처럼의 예의가 없어져 버려.
If I fought using swords during the road to the temple, I'd being rude to the dead.
보스가 칼을 봉인했으니까.
Our boss has sealed this sword.
그러고 보니, 무엇을 부탁하러 갔소?
By the way, what were you going to ask for in the temple-dasu?
오, 내일 큰 싸움이 있어서 그 승리를 부탁하러 갔다.
Ah, we have a big battle tomorrow, so I was going to ask for the victory.
저런, 벌써 시간이 되었구나.
Oh, I must hurry up.
자! 형제! 연이 있다면 또 보자!
Bye, brother! See you again if we are destined to!
싸움의 승리를 빌겠소!
I'll pray for your defeat in the fight-dasu!
고마워!
Thanks!
이야, 멋지오...
He's awesome-dasu!
그럼 나도 가겠소!
Then I'll go too-dasu!
손님!
Customer!
계산 부탁드립니다!
Please pay up!
어? 계산은 이시마츠 씨가 한 게 아니오?
Huh? Didn't Mr. Ishimatsu paid you-dasu?
아니요, 전혀! 단고 50봉 딱 100문이오!
Nope, not at all! 50 dangos, total 100 mons!
어, 그렇게 말해도 없는 것은 어쩔 수 없소...
Even if you say so, I can't pay what I don't have-dasu...
손님!
Dear customer!
계산하지 않고 달아날 생각이십니까?
Are you going to run away without paying?
아니아니아니아니, 그럴 생각은...
Nononono, that's not it...
형, 꽤나 곤란해졌나 보군.
Bro, it seems that you're troubled.
그렇다면 내가 대신 계산해 줄까.
Then should I pay for you instead?
어, 정말입니까?
Really-dasu?!
그 대신 말야, 우리 두목이 있는 곳에서 조금만 아르바이트를 해라.
Instead, I'd like you to do a part-time job in my boss' place.
아르바이트?
Part time job?
그래, 어떻게 하든 그냥은 내줄 수 없지.
Yes. There's no way I'm paying for you for nothing.
먹는 것도 마시는 것도 마음대로.
You can eat and drink as you wish.
게다가 용돈까지 주지.
Moreover, I'll pay you some pocket money.
우와! 하겠소! 무슨 일이 있어도 하게 해 주시오!
Wow! I'll do it-dasu! Please let me do it whatever it takes-dasu!
좋다! 그러지!
Great! Will do so!
맛있소.
So good-dasu.
한 그릇 더 주오!
One more dish-dasu!
잘 먹네, 아까 단고 죽을 정도로 쳐먹은 주제에.
You eat pretty well, for one who already ate dangos to death.
난 칼뿐만이 아니라 먹는 것도 지팡구 제일의 무예가를 꿈꾸오.
I'm seeking to be the number one of not only swords, but also eating-dasu.
오, sorotte to nanigai, 형도 에도토피아에서 열리는 지팡구 무예 대회에 출전할 생각이야?
Oh, by the way, are you also planning to participate in Jipangu Martial Arts Competition in Edotopia?
물론이오.
Of course-dasu.
뭐가 이상하오!
What's so funny-dasu?!
너같은 꼬맹이가 무예 대회에 간다고?
Do you think a brat like you can participate?
너무 많이 먹어서 얘가 돌았나?
I guess he's out of his mind because he must be so full by now.
뭣이오? 내 솜씨도 모르고, 실례이오!
What did you say-dasu? That's a discourtesy to me, when you don't know my capability-dasu!
흥! 그럼 내가 한 수 보여주지!
Hmph! Then I'll show you that you wouldn't!
지로베!
Jirobe!
안심하시오! 칼등이오!
No need to worry-dasu! I hit him with back side of sword-dasu!
잘도 동생에게 치욕을 남겼구나.
How dare you defame my younger brother.
그만둬 주십쇼!
Please stop!
쿠로코마
Kurokoma
무슨 일이 있었는지는 모르지만 이곳에선 쿠로코마의 카츠조의 낯을 세워주길 바라니
While I don't know what happened here, since I'd like if you saved my face,
둘 다 칼을 집어넣어 주십시오.
please put your swords inside.
-아니, 이 녀석이...
-모두에게는 내일의 싸움으로 모두 열심히 해야만 합니다.
-No, this guy...
-We all have to prepare for tomorrow's battle.
-아니, 그래도! -
-관둬 주십시오!
-But still...
-Please stop!
꼬맹아, 기억해 두겠다.
I'll remember this, you brat.
저런, 나쁜 모습을 보여드렸구려.
I apologize for showing you such bad things.
괜찮소. 그보다도 싸움이라니 누구하고 하오?
It's alright-dasu. Anyway, who are you fighting with-dasu?
지로초 일가하고 하오.
Against Jirochou family.
저런, 이시마츠 씨하고 싸움이라...
It's bad. A battle against Mr. Ishimatsu...
어라, 뭔가 문제라도?
Do you have any problem with that?
아, 아니오, 딱히 큰 일 아니오.
N- no, it's nothing serious-dasu.
이건 곤란해졌소...
This is bad-dasu...
본의 아니게 이시마츠와 싸우게 되고 만 무사시. 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Musashi has to fight against Ishimatsu unwillingly. Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
식물도 자는 야밤중.
In the dead of night.
이곳 카츠조 일가의 미닫이문은 스윽 열렸다.
A sliding door of Katsuzou family house has opened.
다행히도 아무도 없소.
Thankfully nobody's here-dasu.
나 이시마츠 씨하고 싸우면 안 되니까...
I must not fight against Mr. Ishimatsu-dasu...
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
이런 밤에 어디 가셔요?
Where are you going in this deep night?
아니, 아, 그게 잠깐 화장실에.
Uh, that is, to toilet.
오, 화장실은 저쪽이지만...
Oh dear, the toilet is at there...
설마 달아날 생각이냐!
Are you planning to run away?!
어이, 손님에게 무슨 소리입니까.
Hey, watch your mouth when you're talking to a guest!
죄송합니다, 두목.
Sorry, boss.
너, 아니, 당신은 아까 족히 10인분은 될 만큼은 먹었지요.
You brat- no, you've ate about ten times of a normal person.
그 만큼은 일하지 않으면 저도 곤란해집니다!
If you don't work as much as you ate, that'll be a problem.
설마 달아나거나 한다면 가진 거 다 가져갈 테니까 알았냐! 입니다.
If you try to run away or something, I'll take everything from you and beat you up! I'm being polite.
아, 아니, 그, 그래, 단지 칼 휘두르는 연습을 하고 있었을 뿐이오.
Uh, no, that is... just... I was just practicing with my swords.
이야, 무예가라는 건 하루라도 연습을 쉬면 안 되오.
Being a Martial Artist, I must not rest practicing for a single day-dasu.
그건 참으로 기쁜 소리군요!
Hearing that truly makes me happy!
내일의 싸움은 잘 부탁드리오.
Please do your best in tomorrow's battle.
그래도 어째서 지로초 일가하고 싸우는 것이오?
But, why are you fighting against Jirochou family-dasu?
그건 지로초 일가가 이 시메즈미 항구를 지배하려고 해서 그렇습니다.
That is because Jirocho family is trying to rule over this Shimezumi harbor.
지로초 일가라는 것은 너무한 놈들의 패거리로 자신들의 마음에 들지 않는 것이 있으면 그새 칼을 쳐들어
Jirochou family is a bunch of bad guys who always pull out their swords whenever they find something they don't like,
아이들을 울게 하고 신호를 안 지키고 나쁜 일만 하오.
and they make children cry and don't keep the traffic lights - they only do bad things.
그렇게 나쁜 녀석들인 것이었소...? 그렇게 보이지 않았는데.
Were they really that bad-dasu? They didn't look like-dasu...
그게 함정이오! 처음에는 착한 얼굴로 가까이 다가와서 상대가 방심할 때 칼을 꺼내...
That's the trap! They approaches you with a kind face, and when you relieve, they pull out their swords and...
저는 지로초 일가에게 고통을 당한 사람들을 구하기 위해 일어났어요.
I stood up to help the people suffering from Jirochou family.
그랬던 것이었소? 사정을 모르고 달아나려 해서 미안하오.
Was that so-dasu? I apologize for trying to run away, not knowing the situation-dasu.
내일은 맡겨만 주시오.
Leave tomorrow to me-dasu.
잘 부탁드립니다.
Please do so.
알겠소!
Got it-dasu!
이윽고 날이 밝았다. 후지산이 보이는 들판에 지로초 일가와 카츠조 일가가 만났다.
And a new day came. Jirochou family and Katsuzou family have met in a field where Mt. Fuji was visible.
이시마츠 씨, 어쩌다 불량한 자들의 동료가 되었소?
Mr. Ishimatsu, why did you become a comrade of bad guys-dasu?
어이! 지로초! 오늘로 시미즈 항에서 원하는 대로 하지 못할 줄 알아라!
Hey! Jirochou! You're not going to do as you want in Shimizu Harbor!
지로초
Jirochou
그건 내가 할 말이다! 지금이라도 늦지 않았으니 생명이 중하다면 항복하고 바로 돌아가거라!
That's what I was going to say to you! It's not too late, so if you value your life, you'd better go back right now!
시끄럽다! 공격해라!
Shut your mouth! Go for it!
당했다!
I've hit!
칼등이오!
I hit with back side-dasu!
뭐라? 칼등?
What? Back side?
그거 참 잘 됐네. 그럼 간다!
That's good to know. Then here it goes!
승부는 내 승리이오!
This match is my victory-dasu!
이건 시합이 아니다! 번듯한 싸움이야!
This is not a match! This is a real fight!
끈질기오!
You're persistent-dasu!
이번이야말로 내 승리이오.
This definitely is my victory-dasu.
흥, 칼이 없어도 이녀석이 있다!
Hmph, I have this even without a sword!
어이! 뭐하나!
Hey! What are you doing?!
밥을 먹었으면 열심히 일하라 했는데 이러면 곤란해!
I told you to do your best since you ate a lot, but this wasn't what I expected!
안 돼... 나, 나...
No... I can't...
뭐, 뭔 짓이오!
Wh- what are you doing-dasu?!
체, 무식한 놈이군!
Hmph, you must be an idiot!
뭐, 뭣이오! 난 동료이오!
Wh- what is this-dasu? I am your comrade!
흥, 그런 건 상관 없어! 어제 잘도 창피를 당하게 했겠다!
Hmph, that doesn't matter! How dare you embarass me yesterday?!
여기서 끝장을 내 주겠다!
I'll finish you right now!
어, 어라?
Huh?!
죽어라, 꼬맹아!
Die, you brat!
아, 안 되오, 손떨림이 멈추질 않소.
I can't-dasu... My hand won't stop shaking-dasu!
이시마츠 씨!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
좀만 늦었으면 당했을 뻔했잖아!
It was a close call!
왜 칼을 안 꺼냈냐!
Why didn't you pull out your sword?
그래도... 그래도 나...
But... but I...
나 손이 떨려서...
I... my hands were shaking...
알겠다. 알았어, 무사시.
I get it. All right, Musashi.
이시마츠 씨!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
나, 나 무서웠소!
I... I was scared-dasu!
이자식! 울 거였다면 애초부터 이 싸움에 오지 않았으면 됐잖아!
You idiot! If you were going to cry, you shouldn't have come to this battle!
그건 이시마츠 씨 잘못이오!
That's your fault-dasu!
어? 내가? 무슨 말이니?
Huh? My fault? What are you talking about?
나, 이시마츠 씨를 응징하러 왔소. 지로초 일가가 시미즈 항구를 지배하려는 나쁜 놈들이라 들었으니까.
I came to punish you-dasu. I heard that Jirochou family are the bad guys who're trying to take over Shimizumi harbor-dasu.
멍청하긴! 그건 카츠조 일가 말이다!
You idiot! That's Katsuzou family!
우리의 원수!
This is a revenge!
이시마츠 씨!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
끝장이다!
I'll finish you!
나, 나 태어나서 처음으로 사람을 베고야 말았소...
I... I cut a person for the first time-dasu...
이시마츠 씨! 괜찮소?
Mr. Ishimatsu! Are you all right-dasu?
무사시... 진검 승부는 말야, 상대가 죽는가 자신이 죽는가의 문제로 칼을 뽑는다는 것은 죽을 각오를 하는 거야.
Musashi... A real fight is a decision of death of your enemy or yourself.
To pull out your sword is to prepare for your own death.
이시마츠 씨!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
무사시. 나도 이제 끝이구나.
Musashi. I am now over.
무슨 말이오! 무슨 약한 말을! 이시마츠 씨답지 않소!
What are you talking about-dasu?! What's up with this weak talk?! That's not like you-dasu!
무사시. 꼭 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되어라. 나는 저 세상에서 그리 되기를 기다리고 있을 테니까.
Musashi. You will become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu. I will look forward for you to be one in the afterworld.
되겠소... 꼭 되어 보이겠소!
I will-dasu... I will become one-dasu!
그러니까 이시마츠 씨도!
So, please, Mr. Ishimatsu!
이시마츠 씨!
Mr. Ishimatsu!
어이! 지로초! 슬슬 빌 때가 되지 않았나?
Hey, Jirochou! Isn't it time for you to beg for your life?
나는 시미즈 항에서 열심히 일하는 약자를 괴롭히는 자는 용서하지 않는다!
I do not forgive anyone who harass the hardworking weak people working in Shimizu Harbor!
흥! 뭔 웃기는 소리냐. 빨리 저 세상에나 떨어져라!
Hmph! You're making me laugh! Just fall to that next world!
멈추시오!
Stop right there-dasu!
잘도 날 속였겠소! 용서할 수 없소!
How dare you deceive me-dasu! Unforgivable-dasu!
흥, 지금 깨달아봤자 늦었다. 먼저 저 세상으로 가라!
Hmph, your realization was too late. Go to hell first!
각오해라, 카츠조!
Be prepared, Katsuzou!
생명은 구해 주십시오.
Please save my life.
나, 칼을 쥐지 않은 자는 베지 않소!
I do not cut one without a sword-dasu.
쳐먹어라!
Eat this!
그러나 이 쪽도 용서 못 하오!
But still I won't forgive-dasu!
너 때문이 이시마츠 씨가 죽었잖소!
Mr. Ishimatsu is dead because of you-dasu!
지로초 두목!
Jirochou boss!
이만 손을 놓을 때다.
It's time to let go.
얼마나 때린다고 해도 이시마츠는 살아 돌아오지 않는다.
No matter how much you hit him, Ishimatsu won't come back.
이시마츠 씨... 나... 나...
Mr. Ishimatsu... I... I...
무사시, 꼭 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되어라!
Musashi, you will become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu!
이시마츠와의 우정 속에서 무사시는 깨달았다. 죽는다는 것을.
Musashi has realized what is to die, from the friendship between Ishimatsu.
그리고 언젠가 자신도 적의 칼 앞에 쓰러지는 날이 올 지도 모른다는 것을.
And that a day might come that he dies by a sword of his opponent.
그러나 namekuna, 무사시! 오늘은 쓰라려도 밝은 내일이 기다리고 있다!
But don't ~, Musashi! Today might have been bitter, but tomorrow will be bright!
나아가라, 무사시! 영광으로의 길을!
Advance, Musashi! To the road to the glory!
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of the empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
a morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't care too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep doing! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how future also is! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
재밌었던 길 끝에 드디어 에도토피아에 도착한 것도 잠시,
After a long and fun road, I finally reached Edotopia,
나는 악인을 돕고 말아, 제니가탄 두목에게 잡히고 말았소.
but I helped a villain and I've captured by the boss Zenigatan-dasu.
빨리 진범을 찾아내지 못하면 난 무예 대회에 나갈 수 없게 되오!
If I fail to find the real criminal soon, I can't register for the martial arts competition-dasu!
두목, 어떻게 좀 해 주시오!
Boss, please do something-dasu!
다음 이야기! 꽃도 폭풍도 에도토피아
Next story! Flower and Storm at Edotopia
질풍노도의 죄인잡기를 보시오!
Watch the stormy arresting story-dasu!
다음 이야기
꽃도 폭풍도 에도토피아
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Flower and Storm at Edotopia
Look forwards for it!